(
"ai_sub_version": "3.3.0",
"generated_at": "2026-07-14T23:05:31.785157",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
唸るぜ 血泥ついたって 守りたい
I'll howl! Even covered in blood and mud, I want to protect you.
革命道中だって 君に夢中
Even in the midst of revolution, I'm crazy about you.
暗闇 染み込む世界で見つけた
Found you in a world steeped in darkness...
センチメンタルな恋
...a sentimental love.
革命道中
[Song: Revolutionary Journey]
甘くぬるい 弛んだ眼差し
A sweet, lukewarm, and relaxed gaze.
変に色気あるから困った
It's troubling because it's strangely alluring.
手を繋ぐ 勇気出したくて
Wanting to summon the courage to hold your hand...
身の程はわきまえて出来やしない
...I just can't seem to know my place.
暗いトンネルの壁 滴り落ちる秘密
Secrets dripping down the dark tunnel walls...
しめやかに高鳴る鼓動
...as my heartbeat quietly races.
ダメ ダメ
No, no!
待て 待て
Wait, wait!
呪いも 病も 抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even the curses and illnesses.
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
Is it okay if I run wild around here?
あぁ 唸る
Ah, groaning...
魂(ちから)ついたって 守りたい
Even if my soul gains strength, I want to protect you.
革命途中 だって 君に夢中
Even mid-revolution, I'm crazy about you.
暗闇 染み込む 世界で 見つけた
Found you in a world where darkness seeps in...
センチメンタルな恋
...a sentimental love.
ダメダメ
No, no!
待て待て
Wait, wait!
なりふり構わず 側にいたい
I want to be by your side, no matter how I look.
不器用な君に 期待しちゃうよ
I can't help but expect things from clumsy you.
しがみつけば 消えそうな 火に
To the fire that seems like it would go out if clung to...
恋の爪立てて 近づいて
...sinking the claws of love, getting closer.
身を任せただからって 全て失ってもいい
Just because I surrendered myself, I don't mind losing everything.
しめやかに 高鳴る心
Quietly, my heart throbs.
ダメダメ
No, no!
待て待て
Wait, wait!
呪いも 病も 君となら
If I'm with you, even curses and illnesses...
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
...is it okay if I run wild around here?
あぁ 泣けば
Ah, if I cry...
絶句しちゃうまで 離れない
...I won't let go until I'm speechless.
革命途中 だって 君に夢中
Even mid-revolution, I'm crazy about you.
揺蕩う 旅の 狭間で 見つけた
Found you in the midst of a swaying journey...
センチメンタルな恋
...a sentimental love.
突き進むなら 二人で
If we push forward, let's do it together.
革命途中 だって 夢に熱中
Even mid-revolution, I'm absorbed in dreams.
ダメダメ
No, no!
待て待て
Wait, wait!
呪いも 病も 抱きしめたい
I want to embrace even the curses and illnesses.
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいよね
It's fine if I run wild around here, right?
怖くたって 唸る
Even if I'm scared, groaning...
魂(ちから)ついたって 守りたい
Even if my soul gains strength, I want to protect you.
革命途中 だって 君に夢中
Even mid-revolution, I'm crazy about you.
暗闇 染み込む 世界で 見つけた
Found you in a world where darkness seeps in...
センチメンタルな恋
...a sentimental love.
いくぞー！
Let's go!
そっと 吐き出す ため息を吸い込んだ
I breathed in the sigh that was quietly exhaled,
後悔は 苦い味残して
leaving behind a bitter taste of regret.
いつも なんで？ 肝心なこと言えないまま
Why is it always like this? Unable to say the most important things,
次の 朝日が顔だしてる
as the next morning's sun shows its face.
嫌になった運命を ナイフで
Cutting up this hateful destiny with a knife,
切り刻んで もう一度
shredding it, once more,
やり直したら キミに
if I were to start over,
出会えないかも
I might not meet you again.
僕の声が 響いた
The moment my voice
瞬間に 始まる
echoed, it began...
命のリミット
...the limit of life.
心臓がカウントしてる
My heart is counting down.
叶えても 叶えても
Even if they come true, even if they come true,
終わらない願い
these endless wishes.
汗をかいて 走った
Running covered in sweat,
世界の秒針は
the second hand of the world
いつか止まった
will one day leave me behind
僕を置いていく
as I stand frozen.
あと何回 キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ 僕を
I'm testing myself.
Catch the Moment
一個 幸せを数えるたびに
Every time I count a piece of happiness,
変わっていく 未来に怯えて
I get scared of the changing future,
しまうけど 愛情の...
but still, let's carefully
種を 大切に 育てよう
...nurture the seed of love.
分厚い 雲もやがて
Even the thick clouds will eventually
突き破るかな
be broken through, right?
キミの声が 響いた
Your voice echoed
僕の全身を 通って
through my entire body,
心臓の ドアを
and it's knocking on
ノックしてる
the door of my heart.
「臆病」でも 開けちゃうんだよ
Even if I'm "timid," I'll open it,
信じたいから
because I want to believe.
何にもないと思ったはずの
Beneath my feet where I thought
足元に いつか深く
there was absolutely nothing,
確かな...
one day, deep and firm...
確かな根を生やす
and grow deep, certain roots.
嵐の夜が来たとしても
Even if a stormy night comes,
揺らいだりはしない
I will not waver.
何度でも
Time and time again...
追い付いたり 追い越したり
chasing and surpassing you,
キミがふいに分かんなくなって
whenever I suddenly lose sight of you.
息をしたタイミングが
Just having our breathing
合うだけで嬉しくなったりして
align makes me feel so happy.
集めた一秒を
Can I turn this second I've gathered
永遠にして
into an eternity
行けるかな
as I move forward?
僕の声が響いた
The moment my voice resounded,
瞬間に始まる
everything began.
命のリミット
My heart is counting down
心臓がカウントしてる
the limit of my life.
叶えても 叶えても
No matter how many wishes come true,
終わらない願い
they never truly end.
汗をかいて走った
Drenched in sweat, I ran forward.
世界の秒針が
One day, the clock hands of this world
いつか止まった
will leave me behind
僕を置いていく
as I stand frozen.
あと何回キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ 僕を
It's testing me...
Catch the Moment
逃さないよ 僕は snuff
I won't let it slip away.
この瞬間を掴め
I'll seize this moment!
Catch the Moment
こんばんドドドー！
Good evening-dododo!
お誕生日を2回迎えることとなった角巻わためです！
This is Tsunomaki Watame, who gets to celebrate her birthday twice!
本当は6月6日がお誕生日なんですけど、不具合が多くて中断、そして延期になり…
Actually, my birthday is June 6th, but due to many technical issues, it was cut short and postponed...
今日！角巻わため生誕祭2026「アニソンナイトフィーバー2」を改めて開催させていただくことになりました！
And today! We are holding Tsunomaki Watame's Birthday Celebration 2026 "Anisong Night Fever 2" once again!
迅速に動いてくださった運営さんたち！
Huge thanks to the staff members who took action so quickly!
そしてライブを見に来てくれている皆さん！本当にありがとうございます！
And to everyone who came to watch the live show! Thank you so much!
1曲目「革命デュアリズム」、2曲目「Catch the Moment」と見ていただいて、分かった方もいらっしゃるかもしれないんですが
Since you've watched the 1st song "Kakumei Dualism" and 2nd song "Catch the Moment", some of you might have noticed...
前回のライブで放送した部分は、万が一のために録画を回してくださっていたので
The parts broadcast during the previous live show were recorded just in case.
そちらの6月6日のバキバキ生誕当日のパフォーマンスを見ていただいて
So, you got to watch those high-energy performances recorded on my actual birthday, June 6th.
それ以外のソロ、MCは、改めてこれ以上ライブ延期にならないように
As for the other solos and MC parts, to prevent any further postponements,
今回は事前に収録をさせていただきました！
we pre-recorded them this time!
なので、未来のリアルタイムのみんなのコメントを予知しながらMCしたいなと思いますので、いっぱいコメントしてください！
So, I'll be doing my MC while predicting everyone's real-time comments from the future, so please leave lots of comments!
うんうん、分かったよ。はい、はい、うん。
Yeah, I see. Okay, okay, uh-huh.
あ、ありがとね。おめでとう？ありがとう！見える、見えるぞ！
Oh, thank you. "Happy birthday"? Thank you! I can see them, I can see them!
あはははは！ありがとうございます！
Ahahaha! Thank you so much!
説明はここまで！ここからはいつものライブ！
That's it for the explanation! From here on, it's our usual live show!
今日は生誕ライブなので、たくさんこのライブに向けて準備や練習を本当にたくさんしてきました！
Since today is my birthday live, I've put in an absolute ton of preparation and practice for this!
ぜひ最後まで楽しんで、そしていっぱいお祝いしてもらえると嬉しいです！
I hope you enjoy it to the very end and celebrate a lot with me!
本日のハッシュタグはこちら！
Here is today's hashtag!
6月6日と変わらず、「#角巻わため生誕祭2026」になりますので、たくさんスクショとか、感想とか、ポストしてください！
It's the same as June 6th: "#TsunomakiWatameBirthdayCelebration2026", so please post lots of screenshots and impressions!
目指せ、またトレンド、1位！
Let's aim for the number one trending spot again!
あとでじっくりねっとり、わためも見に行きたいと思ってますので、よろしくお願いします！
Watame will be checking them out thoroughly and deeply later, so thank you!
ということで、ここまでT.M.Revolutionさんの「革命デュアリズム」、ソードアート・オンラインの「Catch the Moment」と歌わせていただいたんですが
So, I've sung T.M.Revolution's "Kakumei Dualism" and Sword Art Online's "Catch the Moment"...
アニメや原曲MVに関連している演出を入れ込んだりしているので、みんな分かったかな？
We've incorporated references to the anime and the original music videos in the staging, so did you all catch them?
たぶん、わためいとなら分かったかな？
I bet the Watamates noticed them, right?
ぜひ細かいところまで見てもらえると嬉しいです！
I'd be glad if you check out all the small details!
ここからはゲストパートもあります！
From here on, we also have the guest part!
みんなの好きなアニソンも出てくるかも？
Some of your favorite anisongs might pop up!
ということで、ゲストパート、盛り上がっていきましょう！
So, let's keep the excitement going for the guest part!
割れた鏡の中
In the shattered mirror...
映る君の姿
Reflecting your figure.
泣いている 泣いている
Crying, crying,
細い月をなぞる指
Tracing the thin moon with my finger.
誰を呼んでいるの
Who are you calling for,
消えた恋の背中
the back of vanished love?
何度でも 何度でも
No matter how many times,
君の窓を叩くから
I'll keep knocking on your window.
夜の加速度に
Pushed by the acceleration of the night,
背中押されて
pushed from behind,
糸が切れる様に
like a thread about to break,
ただ、君を 君を強く
I just held you, held you...
抱いてた
...tightly.
アンバランスな
Exchanging an...
Kissを交わして 愛に近づけよ
...unbalanced kiss, getting closer to love.
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も
Your tears and sad lies,
僕の心に
in my heart,
眠れ
sleep.
昨日への Merry-go-round
Yesterday's merry-go-round
君を運んでゆく
carrying you away.
止めたくて 止めたくて
Wanting to stop, wanting to stop,
僕は鍵を探してる
I'm searching for the key.
崩れ落ちそうな
Supporting the sky
空を支えて
that's about to collapse,
ひとり立ち尽くす
standing alone.
ただ、君の 君の側に
I just want to be...
いたいよ
...by your side.
アンバランスな
Drawn with an...
Kissで書かれた ふたりのシナリオ
...unbalanced kiss, the scenario of the two.
愛と呼ぶほど 強くなくても
Even if not as strong as love,
君のすべてが
all of you
痛い
hurts me.
ただ、君の 君の側に
I just want to be...
いたいよ
...by your side.
アンバランスな
Exchanging an...
Kissを交わして 愛に近づけよ
...unbalanced kiss, getting closer to love.
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も
Your tears and sad lies,
僕の心に
in my heart,
眠れ
sleep.
君の心が僕を呼ぶまで
Until your heart calls out to me,
抱きしめあえる
until the day we can
日まで
embrace each other.
GHOST SWEEPER
[Title: GHOST SWEEPER]
長い髪なびかせて
Swaying long hair,
悩ましげなボディ
with a provocative body.
この都会を
Walking around this city...
ハイヒールで
...in high heels.
飛び回れば
If I jump around,
Big money coming, yeah!
摩天楼の足下
Under my feet, at the skyscraper,
時代錯誤の罠
there's an outdated trap.
血迷った
If I encounter people...
危ない奴らなら
...who are crazy and dangerous,
極楽へいかせちゃうわ
I'll send them to heaven.
大胆な
I'll let you choose...
私の業の中 どれでも
...whichever of my bold moves.
大胆な私の業のどれでも
Out of my bold tricks,
スキなのをあげる
I'll give you whichever one you like.
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
行き場のない
Because you are a ghost...
あなた Ghost だから…
...with nowhere to go.
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
私が今
Now I'm...
見つけ出して…
...finding you...
Ghost Sweeper
吸印もいいけれど
Absorption is fine,
神通棍はどう？
but how about the spiritual staff?
わがままは 許さないわ
I won't allow selfishness,
逃がせないの Big money coming, yeah
I can't let you escape. Big money coming, yeah!
コンシャスなドレスから
From conscious dresses
ゴージャスなライフも
to a gorgeous life,
いつだって 後からついてくる
they always follow behind me.
それが私のスタイル
That is my style.
クールだと 誰かがいうけれど 必ず
Someone says I'm cool, but I will always...
幸せをあげる
...give you happiness.
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
行き場のない
Because you are a ghost...
あなた Ghost だから…
...with nowhere to go.
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
私が今
Now I'm...
見つけ出して…
...finding you...
Ghost Sweeper
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
行き場のない
Because you are a ghost...
あなた Ghost だから…
...with nowhere to go.
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
私が今
Now I'm...
見つけ出して…
...finding you...
Ghost Sweeper
魂の色は
What color is...
何色ですか
...the soul?
ANIMA
[Song: ANIMA]
「もういっそ 折れたままで」
"Might as well just leave it broken."
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
I'm not strong enough to abandon it...
強くないよ
...or to run away from it.
ほら もう一度
Look, once again...
鼓動、高鳴る
...the heartbeat quickens.
何が正しいかなんて
I don't know what's right...
わからないけど
...but still...
形のないものばかりが
...only things without form...
大切になって行く
...are becoming important.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only unadorned words...
強く結ばれてる
...are strongly connected.
また 躓いて 転がって
Stumbling and rolling again,
それでも 砕けない
but still not broken.
魂の色は
What color is...
何色ですか
...the soul?
ただ 傷ついて 強がって
Just getting hurt and acting tough,
それでも 見つけたいよ
but still wanting to find it...
魂のカタチ
...I'm confirming...
確かめてるよ
...the shape of the soul.
深い地の底で一人
Alone in the depths of the earth,
扉と鍵を探す
searching for doors and keys.
おとぎ話は
Fairy tales, look...
ほら
...look...
泡の様に全部消えて
...they all disappear like bubbles.
葛藤、残像だけ
Only the conflict, the afterimages...
次のページへ
...to the next page.
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて
The growing branches separate,
それぞれの道を行く
each going their own way.
寂しい思い出だけが
Only lonely memories
強く 根を張っている
take deep root.
また貫いて 失って それでもくじけない
Piercing through again, losing things, but still not giving up.
心はどこに
Where is the heart?
器はどこに
Where is the vessel?
ただ残されて 抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Simply left behind, falling away, but I still want to convey it.
魂の理由を
The reason for my soul...
魂の意志を
...the will of my soul...
繋ぐ
...I will connect them.
魂の色は
What color is...
何色ですか
...the color of the soul?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
What color is...
何色ですか
...the color of the soul?
透明な過去に
In a transparent past,
不透明な明日に
in an opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは
you who live,
何色ですか
what color are you?
またつまずいて 転がって それでも砕けない
Stumbling again, rolling, but still not breaking.
魂の色は
What color is...
何色ですか
...the color of the soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt, pretending to be strong, but I still want to find...
魂のカタチ
...the shape of the soul.
確かめてるよ
I'm confirming it.
繋ぐ
Connecting it...
イェーイ！ 3曲連続でお届けしましたが、みんな楽しんでますかー？
Yay! I performed three songs in a row. Is everyone having fun?
みんな楽しんでますかー？
Is everyone having fun?!
快適に見れてますかー？
Are you able to watch it smoothly?!
いや、「幽雅に咲かせ、墨染の桜」の「アンバランスなKissをして」は、月をね、映してもらったり
For "Unbalance na Kiss o Shite" with "Ghostly Band - Phantom Butterfly", we had the moon shown on screen,
戦闘シーンをイメージして、炎に囲まれていたり
and it was surrounded by flames to evoke a battle scene.
ダンスの振りにもね、キャラクターの技が、入っていたりしておりまして
Even the dance choreography incorporated the characters' moves.
ゴーストスイーパー美神の「GHOST SWEEPER」にも、お札をね、持っている振りが、あったり
For "GHOST SWEEPER" from Ghost Sweeper Mikami, there was a move where I hold a paper charm,
あとは、幽霊が、飛んでいるそんな演出が、あったりしましたー！気付いたかな？
and there was also an effect where ghosts were flying around! Did you notice?
そして、ソードアート・オンラインの「ANIMA」は、いつか歌いたいと思っていた曲で
And "ANIMA" from Sword Art Online is a song I've wanted to sing for a long time.
えー、満を持しての披露だったんですが、いかがだったでしょうかー？
I've finally performed it with full preparation. How did you like it?
いやー、カッコよかったなー！すごーいな！わためバキバキだなー！
Man, that was so cool! Amazing! Watame was so sharp!
では！えー、まだこれで、終わりではありません！
Now then! This is not the end yet!
ここからは、鏡ゲートを使ったギミックや、やってみたかった演出なども入ってくるので
From here on, we'll have gimmicks using mirror gates and performances I've always wanted to try...
さらに！盛り上がる、爆上げステージを、いっぱいやっていきたいと思います！
...so I want to do lots of hyped-up stages to get everyone even more excited!
それでは！行ってきまーす！
Well then! Off I go!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
An invincible smile ruining the media
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
I want to know her secret, mysterious
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even her flaws are within her area
完璧で嘘つきな君は
You are perfect and a liar
天才的なアイドル様
a genius idol.
今日何食べた？
"What did you eat today?"
好きな本は？
"What's your favorite book?"
遊びに行くなら
"If you go out to play,"
どこに行くの？
"where do you go?"
何も食べてない
"I haven't eaten anything."
それは内緒
"That's a secret."
何を聞かれても のらりくらり
No matter what she's asked, she dodges smoothly.
そう淡々と だけど燦々と
So nonchalantly, yet brilliantly
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
The secrets that seem visible but are not, taste like honey.
あれもないないない
Not that, no, no, no,
これもないないない
not this, no, no, no.
好きなタイプは？ 相手は？
"What's your favorite type? Your partner?"
さあ答えて
"Come on, answer!"
「誰かを好きになることなんて
"About falling in love with someone..."
私分からなくてさ」
...I don't really understand that."
嘘か本当か知り得ない
Whether it's a lie or the truth is impossible to know.
そんな言葉に
With words like that,
また一人堕ちる
another person falls.
また
Once again,
好きにさせる
I'll make you fall in love.
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone is captivated by you,
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
you are the perfect and ultimate idol.
金輪際現れない
Never to appear again,
一番星の生まれ変わり
the reincarnation of the brightest star.
あー
Ah,
その笑顔で愛してるで
with that smile, saying "I love you,"
誰も彼も虜にしていく
you captivate everyone and anyone.
その瞳がその言葉が
Even if those eyes and those words
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
are lies, that is a perfect love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Right, right, she is so special.
我々は端からおまけです
We are just extras from the start.
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We are just the backup characters for the star.
全てがあの子のおかげなわけない
There's no way everything is thanks to her.
しゃらくさい
How annoying.
妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
There's no way there's no jealousy and envy.
これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
This isn't a joke, which is why it's unforgivable.
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない
If you aren't perfect, it's unforgivable.
自分は許せない
I can't forgive myself.
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I won't accept anyone except you, who are stronger than anyone.
誰もが信じ崇めてる
Everyone believes and worships you,
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
truly the strongest, undefeated idol.
弱点なんて見当たらない
No weaknesses can be found,
一番星を宿している
housing the brightest star.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
You must never show your weaknesses.
知りたくないトコは見せずに
Without showing what they don't want to know,
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
you must be one of a kind, no exceptions.
それこそ本物のアイ
That is indeed true love.
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
With your signature smile, rocking the media,
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
keeping this secret completely hidden.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
A career built on the lie of "I love you,"
これこそ私なりの愛だ
this is my own way of showing love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Even the flowing sweat is a beautiful aqua.
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
These eyelids hiding rubies.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
Singing and dancing, I am Maria.
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
Yes, lies are the ultimate form of love.
誰かに愛されたことも
Having never been loved by anyone,
誰かのこと愛したこともない
and never having loved anyone either,
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当にとなること
I believe that my lie will one day
信じてる
become reality.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
One day, I will surely get everything.
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
I am such a greedy idol.
渡狸とキッスを
And a kiss with Watanuki
ミルフィーユ ワッフル ポンポン
Mille-feuille, waffle, bonbon
ムース 渡狸パイ
Mousse, Watanuki pie
シュークリーム バナナゼリー
Chou à la crème, banana jelly
ババロア 渡狸
Bavarois, Watanuki
ホットケーキ バームクーヘン
Pancake, baumkuchen
渡狸 ワタヌキ
Watanuki, Watanuki
バター 渡狸クレープ
Butter, Watanuki crepe
ワタヌキ 渡狸
Watanuki, Watanuki
ワタヌキとごはん
Watanuki and rice
ワタヌキとおやつ
Watanuki and snack
ワタヌキと肉まん
Watanuki and pork bun
ワタヌキと北京ダック
Watanuki and Peking duck
みつまめ 渡狸
Mitsumame, Watanuki
渡狸シロップ
Watanuki syrup
金時 渡狸
Kintoki, Watanuki
大盛り 渡狸丼
Big bowl of Watanuki bowl
ぼんやり
Daydreaming...
夢見てごらん
Why don't you dream?
ハチミツみたいにとろける
Melting away like honey
愛、上、お菓子、下
Love, above, sweets, below
柿食うっけ？ こんなにも
Ka, Ki, Ku, Ke, are you eating persimmons? Like this too
さしすせ ソフトクリーム
Sa, Shi, Su, Se, soft-serve ice cream
五臓六腑でいこう
Let's go with full force
たちつて トルテ来た
Ta, Chi, Tsu, Te, torte has come
なにぬね のり塩
Na, Ni, Nu, Ne, salted seaweed
はっ！ヒフヘ ホットパイと
Ha! Hi, Fu, He, with hot pie
二人でぬくぬく
The two of us, nice and warm
まみむめ モンブラン
Ma, Mi, Mu, Me, Mont-Blanc
やいゆえ ヨーグルト
Ya, I, Yu, E, yogurt
ラリるれ ロールケーキ
Ra, Ri, Ru, Re, roll cake
渡狸とキッスを
And a kiss with Watanuki
ワタヌキの甘みと
Watanuki's sweetness and
ワタヌキの苦み
Watanuki's bitterness
ワタヌキの酸味で
Watanuki's sourness
好き好きラブ・コンボ
A love combo I love
ようこそジャパリパークへ
[Title: Welcome to Japari Park]
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to, welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today, too, it's a great uproar, tumbling and falling
うー！ がおー！
Grrr! Roar!
高らかに笑い笑えば フレンズ
If you laugh out loud, you're a friend
喧嘩して すっちゃかめっちゃかしても 仲良し
Even if we fight and make a mess, we're best friends
けものは居ても のけものは居ない
Even if there are animals, there are no outcasts
本当の愛はここにある
True love is here
ほら 君も手をつないで大冒険
Come on, hold hands and go on a great adventure
ワン・ツー・スリー
One, Two, Three
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to, welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today, too, it's a great uproar, tumbling and falling
姿かたちも十人十色
Everyone has different appearances and shapes
だから惹かれ合うの
That's why we are attracted to each other
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
If we rest our fingers gently against the twilight sky
はじまりまして
Nice to meet you
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know you more
うー！ がおー！
Grrr! Roar!
振り向けば あちらこちらで トラブル
If you look back, there's trouble here and there
トラブル
Trouble
なんてこった
What the heck
ちんぷんかんぷん
I don't understand any of it
まとまんない
It doesn't add up
けものですもの 大目に見てね
We're animals, so please overlook it
みんな自由に生きている
Everyone is living freely
そう 君も飾らなくたって大丈夫
Yes, you don't have to put on an act either, it's okay
はい どうぞ
Yes, here you go
Nice to meet you \u200eジャパリパーク！
Nice to meet you, Japari Park!
今日からはどうぞよろしくね
From today, I'm counting on you
いつもいつでも優しい笑顔
Always, forever with a kind smile
君を待っていたの
I was waiting for you
開かれた扉 夢をいっぱい語ったら
If we talk a lot about our dreams after the gate is open
どこまででも どこまででも
No matter how far, no matter how far
続いていく グレートジャーニー
It will continue, a great journey
東へ吠えろ
Roar to the east
西へ吠えろ
Roar to the west
世界中に響け サファリメロディ
Let the safari melody echo throughout the world
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to, welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today, too, it's a great uproar, tumbling and falling
姿かたちも十人十色
Everyone has different appearances and shapes
だから惹かれ合うの
That's why we are attracted to each other
夕暮れ空に 指をそっと重ねたら
If we rest our fingers gently against the twilight sky
はじまりまして
Nice to meet you
君をもっと知りたいな
I want to know you more
うー！ がおー！
Grrr! Roar!
ララララ
La-la-la-la
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, Welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ
La-la-la-la
ララララララ
La-la-la-la-la-la
集まれ友達
Gather, my friends
ララララ
La-la-la-la
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, Welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la
素敵な旅立ち
A wonderful departure
ようこそ
Welcome to
ジャパリパークへ！
Japari Park!
Fire, fire
Oh oh oh oh...
Fire, fire, fire
Night of fire!
Fire!
Welcome to my broken low
Welcome to the famous disco live
Come on lady come and go
Come on lady get me once tonight
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door I'll open
Speak my name now, speak it if you know how
Fly to me, get ready for the
Night of fire,
you've better better stay
You've better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire,
come over over me
Come over over the top you've never been here
Night of fire,
you've better better stay
You've better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire,
come over over me
Come over over the top
You'll have a night of fire
Welcome to my rocky show
Welcome to the fire of the night
Come on baby let it go
Come on baby let me stick you tight
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door I'll open
Speak my name now, speak it if you know how
Fly to me, get ready for the
Night of fire,
you've better better stay
You've better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire,
come over over me
Come over over the top you've never been here
Night of fire,
you've better better stay
You've better better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire,
come over over me
Come over over the top you'll have a night of fire
You'll have a night of fire
You've better better stay
The prayer to play
Come over over me
You've never been here
Night of fire,
you've better better begin
come over over the top
you'll have a night of fire
Welcome to my broken low
Welcome to the famous disco live
Come on lady, come and go
Come on lady, get me once and right
Not a danger
not a blacky stranger
Rock it - rock it - knock to my door, I'll open
Speak my name now
speak it if you know how
Fly to me
get ready for the...
Night of fire
You'll have a night of fire
ていうことで！
And with that!
ここまで、たくさんの
Up until now, many,
ホント、たくさんのゲストさんたちと
really, so many guest stars...
歌って踊ってきましたけれど
...have sung and danced with me!
いかがだったでしょうか！
How did you like it?
楽しんでますかー？
Are you having fun?
なかなかね、こんなにホロメンが集まることってないので
It's rare to have so many Hololive members gather,
もう、ホント生誕祭！お祭りって感じで嬉しいです！
so it really feels like a birthday festival! I'm so happy!
ゲストさんたちにも大きな拍手を！
Please give a big round of applause for our guests!
いや、ありがとう、みんな！
Thank you so much, everyone!
ゲストのみんな、ありがとうー！
Thank you to all the guests!
いや、このね、鏡のモニターから登場するという演出を
I really wanted to try appearing from the mirror monitors,
やってみたいなと思って
so I wanted to give it a try...
アイドルトークとスイートパレードで実現していただきました！
...and we did it for "Idol Talk" and "Sweet Parade"!
あの、わためいと、スバルさん、エルフレさん、ルイ友さんたちが
Seeing Watamates, Subaru-san, Elfriends, and Luitomos...
ペンライトをね、振ってくれてたのも可愛かったし
...wave their penlights was so adorable!
やっぱりホロメンって可愛いよなー！
Holo-members really are the cutest, aren't they?
あと、ようこそジャパリパークへでは
Also, for "Welcome to Japari Park"...
サバンナで肉食動物たちに囲まれて
...we were surrounded by carnivores in the savanna,
トラのような人間がいたような気もしますが
and though I felt like a tiger-like human was there...
みんながね、仲良くなっていく様子、表現させていただきました！
...we tried to portray how everyone becomes good friends!
ま、ちょっとね、最後みんなの表情怪しかったけどね
Well, everyone's expressions at the end were a bit suspicious!
そして、ナイト・オブ・ファイヤー！
And then, "Night of Fire"!
これはもう、英語の上手なEN・IDメンバーのみんなと一緒に歌いたいと思って
I wanted to sing this with EN and ID members who are good at English,
横に立って歌っても浮かないように、英語頑張ったんだけど
so I tried my best with English so I wouldn't stand out,
大丈夫だったかな？海外ニキ！
did I do okay? Overseas fans!
うーん、英語上手！英語上手！ってコメントが
I bet comments saying "Great English! Great English!"...
来てると思う！ありがとうございます！
...are appearing right now! Thank you so much!
でも、みんなもっと気になるところがね、あったかなと思うんですが
But I think there's something else everyone might be curious about...
あ、車ね！
Ah, the car!
攻めてたね！
It was pretty bold, right?
あとはパラパラを踊るギリわるロボね！
Also, the Gari-waru robot dancing parapara!
やりたい放題させていただいて、とっても楽しかったです！
I got to do whatever I wanted, and it was so much fun!
でも、まだ終わりじゃない！
But it's not over yet!
ちょっと着替えてくるので、待っててください！
I'm going to quickly change outfits, so please wait a moment!
よいしょ、よいしょ。よいしょ、よいしょ。着替えて、着替えて、よいしょ、よいしょ。ふぅー！
Yoisho, yoisho... Yoisho, yoisho... Changing, changing... Yoisho, yoisho... Whew!
はぁー！あ、もう着替え終わった！
Haa! Ah, I'm already done changing!
さて、次の曲なんですが
Now, about the next song...
なんと！なんかみんな、もう知ってそうだけど
Wait! I feel like you all might already know, but...
次の曲は、新曲！灰色の証明をやります！
...for the next song, I'll perform my new song, "Haiiro no Shoumei"!
わためチャンネルにて、MV公開中なので、MVもぜひ見てください！
The MV is currently out on the Watame Channel, so check it out too!
そして、楽曲リリースもしているので、いいなと思ったらぜひ買ってください！
It's also officially released, so if you like it, please buy it!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much!
では、新曲 灰色の証明
Now, my new song, "Haiiro no Shoumei"...
魂を込めて歌います。聴いてください
...I'll sing it with all my soul. Please listen to it.
灰色の証明
[Song: Gray Proof]
静寂に包まれた
Wrapped in silence...
ゼロ地点の感情を
...my feelings at point zero.
期待を背負っているのは私ではないから
Because I'm not the one carrying those expectations.
主人公はいつだって輝いている誰かで
The protagonist is always someone else shining bright...
見上げるだけじゃ何も変わらない
...simply looking up changes nothing.
今この時だけの瞬間的な優位性で
With a momentary superiority unique to this very instant...
駆け抜けて
...I'll run on through!
灰色の空割いて 私のすべてを
Ripping open the gray sky, my entire self...
運命のシナリオに叩きつけて打ち砕いて
...I will smash against the scenario of fate, breaking it apart!
自信は微塵もない あるのは渇望だけ
There isn't a shred of confidence, only a craving.
ただ自分の生命を証明しよう
I will simply prove my own existence...
此処にいた事を刻むように
...as if carving the proof that I was here.
綺麗な勝ち方は
A beautiful way to win
望むべくもない
is not even worth wishing for.
華やかさも必要ない
Nor is glamour necessary,
それが私だから
because that's who I am.
歴史はいつだって
History is always
勝者が作るモノ
written by the victors,
だけど記憶はその限りじゃない
but memories are not limited to that.
今この時だけは
Only at this very moment,
決断的な刹那性に飛び込んでいけ保存
dive into this decisive, fleeting moment!
灰色の地で描く 私の想いが
My feelings, painted on this grey land...
美しき痛みをも 乗り越えて書き換えていく
...will overcome and rewrite even the beautiful pain.
後悔は1ミリもない
There is not a single millimeter of regret.
あるのは灼熱だけ
All that exists is burning passion.
ただ自分の生命を蹴り上げるように
Just to kick up my own life...
始まりは些細 最早どうだっていい
The beginning was trivial; it doesn't matter anymore.
突き動かされ指先を伸ばす
Driven by impulse, I reach out my fingertips.
現実は残酷だと 気付いていないわけじゃない
It's not that I don't realize reality is cruel.
諦めるその時は 今ではなかったらしい保存
The time to give up was apparently not now.
灰色の空描く もう一度点火して
Painting the grey sky, let's ignite it once more.
ただ自分の生命を証明しよう
Let's simply prove my own life,
そこにいた事を刻むように
as if engraving the fact that I was there.
はい！ということで
Yes! And with that...
新曲「灰色の証明」
...my new song, "Proof of Grey"...
やっと披露できた！やっと証明できた！
...I finally got to perform it! I finally proved it!
聴いてくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for listening!
この楽曲は岸田教団＆THE明星ロケッツの皆さんに製作していただきまして
This song was created for me by Kishida Kyoudan & THE Akeboshi Rockets,
スポーツだったり、みんなが頑張りたい時に力になれるような応援ソングを作りたいと思い
with the hope of creating a cheering song that can give strength to everyone during sports or when they want to do their best.
色々語ったらかなり熱くてカッコいい楽曲に仕上がりました！
After discussing various ideas, it turned out to be a very passionate and cool song!
上手くいかないことがあっても、また立ち上がって前に進む
Even when things don't go well, standing up again and moving forward...
わためにとっても背中を押してくれるそんな特別な楽曲に、今回のライブでなりました！
...through this live show, it has become such a special song that pushes even my back!
みんなにとってもそうだったら嬉しいです
I hope it is the same for all of you!
こちらの新曲MVいっぱい見て、楽曲もぜひ購入して、わための音楽を応援していただけたらとっても嬉しいです！
Please watch the MV for this new song a lot, purchase the song, and support Watame's music—I'd be so happy!
目指せ武道館！
Aiming for Budokan!
と、あ、ここで、まだ告知していないものが一つありまして
And, ah, here, there's one more announcement that I haven't made yet.
ライブじゃないんですけど
It's not about a live concert, but...
なんと！
...surprisingly!
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
「角巻わための Have a nice day」書籍刊行が決定！
A book publication of "Tsunomaki Watame's Have a nice day" has been confirmed!
ということで、ハバナイが本になります！
In other words, "Habanai" is becoming a book!
出版社は、かいけつゾロリやおしりたんていなどで有名なポプラ社様より、オリジナルグッズ付きで12月に刊行予定です！
It is scheduled to be published in December with original merchandise by Poplar Publishing, famous for "Kaiketsu Zorori" and "Oshiri Tantei"!
まだ少し先にはなりますが、楽しみに待っててもらえると嬉しいです！
It's still a little while away, but I'd be happy if you look forward to it!
そして！じゃーん！
And! Ta-da!
今年も角巻わため誕生日記念グッズが受注受付中です！
This year as well, Tsunomaki Watame's Birthday Memorial Merchandise is available for pre-order!
ラインナップを改めて紹介させてください！
Let me introduce the lineup once again!
どどどどん！
Dodododon!
でたー！ふーみママ描き下ろしの、わためのあったかブランケット！
Here it is! Watame's warm blanket illustrated by Fuumi-mama!
なんと、セクシーです！
It is, surprisingly, sexy!
そして、裏面にはわためいとがいます！
And, Watamates are on the back!
丸めるとね、わためいとの形になりますので、2wayでも使えます！
If you roll it up, it takes the shape of a Watamate, so it can be used in two ways!
ぜひ、温もりを感じてください！
Please feel its warmth!
そして、どどどどん！
And, dodododon!
わため＆わためいと温感マグカップ！
Watame & Watamate Thermal Mug!
こちらは、もた先生に描き下ろしていただきまして
This was illustrated by Mota-sensei,
最初は夜の風景なんですけど、温かいものを入れていただくとその熱を感知して
and while it starts as a night scene, when you put a hot drink in, it detects the heat...
朝の景色に柄が変わるような仕様になっております！
...and the design changes to a morning scene!
わための配信を意識してデザインしてもらったので
It was designed with Watame's streams in mind,
配信を見ながらぜひ、温かい飲み物を飲んでくださいね！
so please enjoy a hot drink while watching the streams!
そして、まだあります！どどどどどどどん！
And, there's more! Dododododododon!
わためいとクッション！
Watamate Cushion!
クッションとして使うもよし、飾るもよし、とっても可愛いクッションなので、ぜひお部屋に
You can use it as a cushion, or display it—it's a very cute cushion, so please have it in your room!
に置いてみてください！
...please place it there!
最後に！
And finally...
ドドンドドンドドンドドン！
*drumroll* ...bam!
きたー！わためなりきりアイマスク！
It's here! The Watame Narikiri Eye Mask!
眠っている顔と、わためと言えばこれ！の表情にしていただきました！
We have her sleeping face, and "this is classic Watame!" expression!
果たして需要あるのか、気になる方はぜひなりきりアイマスク手に入れてください！
Is there a demand for this? If you're curious, please get this eye mask!
こちらのグッズをフルセットで購入していただいた方には...
For those who purchase the full set of these goods...
ドドンドドンドドンドドン！
*drumroll* ...bam!
わための直筆サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードと、
You'll get a postcard with Watame's handwritten autograph and message,
角巻わためのショートボイスセット15種類が特典としてついてきます！
plus a set of 15 Tsunomaki Watame short voice clips as a bonus!
今年も無制限で直筆を書かせていただく予定なので、ぜひこの機会にゲットしてみてください！
I plan to hand-sign an unlimited number again this year, so take this opportunity to get yours!
ということで、新曲MV公開中！
And with that, the new song's MV is now out!
楽曲リリース中！
The song is now released!
誕生日グッズ発売中！
Birthday goods are now on sale!
12月、カバー小説単行本刊行決定！
And in December, a Cover novel book publication is confirmed!
よろしくお願いいたします！
Thank you so much!
このあとは、22時15分からメン限アンコールライブもありますので、
After this, we have a member-only encore live starting at 22:15,
よかったらメンゲ、あ、間違えた、メンバーに入っていただいて、引き続き楽しみましょう！
so if you'd like, please join... wait, I mean, become a member and let's keep having fun!
今年はなんと、2Days！
This year is actually a 2-day event!
お誕生日たくさんお祝いしてくれて、ありがとう！
Thank you all so much for celebrating my birthday!
めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです！
I was super, super happy!
それでは、メン限アンコールライブでお会いしましょう！
Well then, see you at the member-only encore live!
まったねー！
See ya!
どうしていつも怒ってばかり
Why are you always just angry?
本当は素直になりたいのに
Even though I really want to be honest
お互いぷいってそっぽ向いて
Both of us huff and turn away
なかよくケンカしな！
Fight nicely!
キミとボクの HIDE & SEEK
You and my HIDE & SEEK
どこに隠れているの？
Where are you hiding?
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet
早く見つけてほしいな
I want you to find me quickly
すれ違ってばかりの毎日だけど
Even though every day is full of passing each other by...
誰より大好きなんだよ
...I love you more than anyone.
だから今日も なかよくケンカしな！
So today too, fight nicely!
追いかけっこはいつだって全力
Chasing each other with all our might
負けず嫌いなキミだから
Because you hate to lose
ちょっと意地悪しちゃうけど
I play a little mean sometimes,
本当はね 寂しいんだよ
but actually, I'm lonely.
夕暮れの風に吹かれて
Blown by the evening breeze,
キミの影を探すけれど
I look for your shadow, but...
どこにも見当たらないな
...I can't find it anywhere.
もしかして もう帰っちゃったの？
Could you have already gone home?
うしろの正面だあれ？
Who is behind me?
ふり向いたらキミがいて
When I turned around, you were there...
にっこり笑ってみせた
...and you showed me a bright smile.
やっぱり大好きだよ
I really do love you after all!
キミとボクの HIDE & SEEK
You and my HIDE & SEEK
どこに隠れているの？
Where are you hiding?
もういいかい？ まーだだよ
Are you ready? Not yet
早く見つけてほしいな
I want you to find me quickly
すれ違ってばかりの毎日だけど
Even though every day is full of passing each other by...
誰より大好きなんだよ
...I love you more than anyone.
だから今日も なかよくケンカしな！
So today too, fight nicely!
なかよくケンカしな！
Fight nicely!
キミとボクの HIDE & SEEK
You and my HIDE & SEEK
いつまでもずっと
Forever and ever,
なかよくケンカしな！
fight nicely!
いつだってそう「僕なんて」さって
It's always like this, "someone like me"...
うつむいてばかりのMayday
just hanging my head down, a Mayday.
つまずいて泣いて
Stumbling, crying,
「どうせ」って口癖が染みついてさ
"anyway" has become a habit.
いつからかまた積もる焦り
Anxiety piles up again since when?
でも胸の奥にある光
But the light deep in my heart...
繋ぐ点と線の上
...connects the dots and lines,
踏み出すイメージの先へ
towards the image of stepping forward.
遠くたっていい ほら 虹をまたいで
It's okay to be far away. Look, cross over the rainbow!
さぁ 心のままに音を奏でる
Come on, play the sound just as your heart wants.
逸る鼓動は今を刻む証だ
The racing heartbeat is proof of etching the "now".
響け 僕らの想いを乗せて
Resound, carrying our thoughts,
高く遠く 歌を紡いで
high and far, weaving the song...
Lalala
季節巡って 駆け抜けて
Seasons go by, running through.
気づけば大人になって
Before I knew it, I became an adult.
幼い日の心は胸の奥くすぶってた
The heart of my childhood days was smoldering deep in my chest.
怖いことも増えたけど
I had more scary things, but
でも今だから見える世界
still, this is the world I can see because of "now".
儚さの中に確かに灯る光
The light that surely shines within the transience...
繋いでいこう さぁ 新しいステージへ
Let's connect it... Come on, to a new stage!